The clouds adorning the setting sun whispered "It's gonna be your turn next" into my ear
But now that they've grown tired of just killing time I'm sure I'll just be their scapegoat
But I'm the king of my very own world
I can even run on top of water
I'm the egg who can put itself back together again after a fall
And can even go on to become an astronaut
I'm sure if I pick up all the beads that rained from the sky and gather them up
Then one day I'll finally be able to plant a flag which signifies my very own liberty
So I pull on my ripped jeans and fight back the tears the draft brings
I exhale a big gulp of air and then another 'cause I'm a boxer rising up again
You only get one chance to come back from the brink
So pound on that door you painted yourself
The colorful ink disperses into two paths
But you're the one who decides how your flower blooms
Kingdom (Part 1)
（モモ）わあ！　すご〜い！
Wow!
Comfy
Rei.
（あかり）零(れい)君
あしたの新人戦 決勝 頑張って
Good luck at the Rookie Tournament finals tomorrow.
And so...
…というわけで
Here.
はい　〝勝つ丼〞
Pork cut-let's win!
Pork cut-let's win
Ta-daa
いただきま〜…
Thank you for the food.
おお！　うまっ！
Delicious!
What?!
えっ？　今 サクッて言った
そして トロッと来た！
It's crispy!
And juicy!
Yummy!
Momo's
cutlet
is cut
in cubes
Momo's
cutlet
is cut
in cubes
おいしい〜！
（モモ）ウ〜ン！
（あかり）でしょう？
I know, right?
I cracked a raw egg on top of the hot pork cutlet.
（あかり）揚げたてのを
トロトロ卵で サッと とじたの
（あかり）あしたは大阪だっけ？
こういうときは前乗りなのね
So you're going to Osaka tomorrow?
You arrive a day early for these kind of events, right?
（零）
あっ はい　関西将棋会館は—
Yes.
The Kansai Shogi Hall has a few rooms available,
so I'll be staying there.
泊まれる部屋も少しあるので
僕は そこに
And Hina, your train leaves at eight tomorrow, right?
ひなは
あしたの８時の新幹線なんだよね
You have to be at school by seven?
学校に７時だっけ？
Nom
You have an early morning, so why don't I draw the bath?
朝早いから
もうお風呂 張っておこうか
Uh, okay.
ひなちゃん　お土産 買ってきてね
Hina, buy me a souvenir!
Sure.
（零）そう　ひなちゃんは
あしたから修学旅行なのだ
That's right.
Hina's field trip starts tomorrow.
Three days and two nights in Kyoto.
京都へ２泊３日
（ひなた）ごちそうさま
Thank you for dinner.
（あかり）あら…
どうしたの？　もういいの？
Oh, what's wrong?
You're done already?
なんか…
何だろう　おなかが痛くて
I don't know what it is, but my stomach hurts.
（あかり）
大丈夫？　油っこすぎたのかな
Are you all right?
Maybe it was too greasy.
It's unusual for you to have a stomachache.
珍しいわね おなか痛いなんて
お薬のむ？
Want some medicine?
Yeah.
ひなちゃん　それは…
Hina, did you...
もしかしたら
痛いのは 胃なのでは？
say your stomach hurts?
There.
（零）そう　右を下にして—
Lie on your right side.
背中をちょっと温(あった)めると
少し楽になるかも
Warming your back like this may make you feel a little better.
Yeah.
（ひなた）うん…　ありがとう
Thank you.
Is she sick?
（ミケちゃん）弱ってるの？
Sniff
Are you okay, Hina?
（クロちゃん）
大丈夫？　ひなちゃん
（零）
彼女の学校での現状を思えば—
When I thought about her situation at school,
I can imagine how this three-day, two-night trip would be painful.
この旅行の２泊３日が
相当 苦しいものであることは—
容易に想像できた
It was plain as day.
（あかり）大丈夫？
Are you okay?
京都
ムリして行かなくてもいいんだよ
You don't have to go to Kyoto, you know.
No, I'll go.
ううん　行く
I have a feeling that I need to go.
（ひなた）
行かなきゃダメな気がする
でないと 私は—
It feels like if I don't,
この先 ずっと何年も—
I'll regret it down the line, years from now,
even after becoming an adult.
大人になってからも
後悔しそうな気がする
I think I wanted memories of not running away.
“逃げなかった”って記憶が
欲しかったんだと思います
Anyway, I can't explain it well,
（高橋(たかはし)）
だから うまく言えないけど—
but you wanted to get rid of things like that, right?
そういうのを
なくしたかったってことですよね？
Back then, Takahashi immediately said he understood.
（零）あのとき 瞬時に
“分かる”と言ってくれた高橋君
（零）ひなちゃん　僕 勝つから
Hina.
I'm going to win.
I swear I'll win.
絶対 勝ってくるから
Nikaidou kept playing until he collapsed.
And the girl in front of me...
そして 目の前の彼女も—
戦っているんだ
is also fighting.
（零）
僕は絶対に 勝って帰ってくるから
I swear I'll win before I come home.
When your stomach feels better, let's all go to a sweets shop.
おなか痛くなくなったら
みんなで甘味屋さんに行こう
（ひなた）あっ…
（零）好きな物 みんな—
You can have whatever toppings you like.
全部のせていいから
Okay.
Thank you, Kiriyama.
ありがとう 桐山(きりやま)君
They're all fighting to win...
（零）みんな たったひとつの
小さな自分の居場所を…
their one little place in the world.
勝ち取るために
あれ？　ここ どこだ？
Huh?
Where am I?
（零）ああ…　そうだ
Oh, that's right.
大阪だ
It's Osaka.
僕は ここに 戦いに来たんだ
I came here to fight.
新人戦は26歳以下
The Rookie Tournament is open to those who are 26 or younger
and no higher than 5-dan.
五段以下の棋戦
決勝は 持ち時間５時間
The finals are a best-of-one,
and each player has a five-hour time limit.
一番勝負
戦いは多分 夜まで続くだろう
The match will probably continue until the evening.
念のため 朝飯と昼飯…
飲み物も多めに買っておこう
To be on the safe side, I'll buy breakfast, lunch,
and plenty of drinks.
Kiriyama is coming today, right?
（棋士Ａ）
今日 桐山 こっちに来てんだろう？
Yeah.
（棋士Ｂ）ああ
俺たちのハッチ泣かしたヤツな
He's the guy who made our Hacchi cry.
（棋士Ａ）この間のボンボンは
気の毒やったけど—
It's too bad what happened to that rich kid, but Yamazaki was going all-out too.
山崎(やまざき)先輩も必死やからな
Yeah.
（棋士Ｂ）そうやな
なんたって 前人未到の—
After all, his unprecedented title of
"Eternal Rookie King" was on the line!
“永世新人王”が
懸かっとるんやもんな
You can't blame him.
（棋士Ａ）しかたないさ
体調管理も将棋のうち
Maintaining your health is part of the game.
（棋士Ｂ）
相手が どんな状態であろうと
全力で倒すのが礼儀
Doing everything you can to win, no matter what
condition your opponent is in, is just proper etiquette.
（棋士Ａ）
順慶(じゅんけい)先輩は 正しく戦ったまでだ
Junkei just fought the way you're supposed to fight.
（零）今になって思う
I suddenly recall what he said.
I'll have my shot at the title.
（二海堂）絶対 タイトル戦に出る
If I didn't think that,
そう思わないで
どうして やっていける？
how could I go on?
（零）二海堂が あの言葉を—
I wonder how strongly Nikaidou felt...
どれほどの気持ちで
口にしていたのかを
when he said those words.
（山崎）間違ってねえよ 桐山零
You're not mistaken, Kiriyama Rei.
Dao is self-derived
Man is derived
from nature
Nature is derived
from Heaven
Heaven is derived
from Dao
新人戦 決勝戦
This is the final match of the Rookie Tournament.
（山崎）俺が 山崎順慶だ
I'm Yamazaki Junkei.
（零）静かだ
It's quiet.
駒の音だけが 空気を震わす
Only the sound of our pieces disturbs the air.
（零）振り穴一直線か
He's gunning for a Ranging Rook Castle.
ガチガチに固めて
長期戦に持ち込む気だな？
He'll lock himself in, intending to make this a drawn-out war.
While playing, the question "Why?"...
指しながらも ずっと
“どうして”という言葉が…
keeps swirling around in my head.
頭の中をグルグルと駆け巡っていた
棋譜を見て 感じた
When I looked at the match records, I sensed it.
You had plenty of moves that were open.
あんた 十分 指せたじゃないか
So why did you force a draw by fourfold repetition?
じゃ なぜ千日手に持ち込んだ？
Because I didn't have a winning move.
（山崎）“決め手に欠けたから”
（棋士Ａ）しかたないさ
体調管理も将棋のうち
You can't blame him.
Maintaining your health is part of the game.
（棋士Ｂ）
相手が どんな状態であろうと
全力で倒すのが礼儀
Doing everything you can to win, no matter what
condition your opponent is in, is just proper etiquette.
（棋士Ａ）
順慶先輩は 正しく戦ったよ
Junkei just fought the way you're supposed to fight.
The guys in the store said he fought the way you're supposed to fight.
（零）“正しく戦った”と
さっきの人たちは言ってたけれど
But if you can't overcome your inability to predict your opponent's moves,
自分の読みの弱さを克服せずに—
and instead you put the blame on people who say that's "the way you're supposed to fight,"
他人に背負わせることを
“正しい”というのなら—
then I have only one thing to say to you.
僕の答えは ただひとつ
Kingdom (Part 1)
〝ふざけるな〞
Go fuck yourself!
Two eyeballs in the dark.
（零）闇に目玉が２つ
They're examining my situation.
こちらの様子をうかがっている
ただ じっと僕のミスを…
Waiting for me to make a mistake.
指し間違う瞬間を…
Waiting with bated breath...
息を潜めて待っている
for the moment I make a wrong move.
He waits patiently.
ただ 淡々と
振り切れない
Like a shadow...
that I can't shake off.
影のように
Kingdom (Part 2)
In that case,
それなら 見せてやるよ
I'll show you.
Whether I make a mistake or not,
俺がミスするかどうか
I'll fling all of...
その泥ごと…
吹っ飛ばしてやる！
that mud away!
Don't try to act cool, Kiriyama!
（二海堂）
カッコつけんな 桐山ぁ！
If you really want to win, then persevere!
本当に勝ちたいんなら粘れ！
Don't just attack, you have to defend!
攻めるだけじゃなく
ちゃんと守れ！
（二海堂）
ついに追いついたぞ 桐山
I finally caught up to you, Kiriyama.
直接対決がかなうことを
楽しみにしてるぜ
I'll be waiting for the day when we have a match together.
（二海堂）なあ ライバル
Right, rival?
桐山　聞こえているか？
Kiriyama, can you hear me?!
もっと自分の将棋を…
自分を大切にしてくれ！
Take better care of your shogi,
and yourself!
僕は いつだって こうだ
I'm always like this.
Bravery and recklessness are similar but different!
潔いのと投げやりなのは
似ているけど 違うんだ！
自分のことで
すぐ いっぱいいっぱいで
I'm always so quick to focus on myself.
零ちゃん ありがとう　次は大丈夫
Thanks, Rei.
I should be okay for the next one.
（零）自分以外の人の優しさとか
Other people's kindness,
or their strength...
強さとか
I'd probably be cleaning up by myself and crying.
これ片づけながら
多分 泣いちゃってたわ
...or their loneliness.
（零）寂しさとか
I never...
全然…
I could never notice it.
本当に いつも気づけなくて
It was frustrating.
悔しくて
I felt so pathetic.
情けなくて
Dao is self-derived
Man is derived
from nature
Nature is derived
from Heaven
Heaven is derived
from Dao
Rookie Tournament Finals
Idiot.
（二海堂）
…カ野郎　ハラハラさせやがって
You really had me worried there.
You did it.
やった…　やったぞ 桐山！
You did it, Kiriyama!
Yes.
（花岡(はなおか)）
はい…　はい　見事でございました
Yes, it was brilliant.
As expected from your dear rival, Master Harunobu.
さすがは
晴信(はるのぶ)さまのライバルでございます
Kansai Shogi Hall
（零）
お世話になりました　失礼します
Thank you for everything.
Goodbye.
（横溝(よこみぞ)）これ よく効くんだよ
島田(しまだ)八段にもらった胃薬
It really works!
Shimada, 8-dan, gave me this stomach medicine.
（棋士Ｃ）へえ
（棋士Ｄ）へえ　どれどれ？
Oh?
Really? Can I see?
俺も胃痛持ちなんスよ
I've got stomach pain too.
It's like magic!
（横溝）効いたねえ
When you have a stomachache because of nerves,
consult Shimada, 8-dan.
やっぱ“神経性の胃痛は
島田八段に聞け”だね
He's the authority on stomach pain.
さすが 胃痛のオーソリティーだけ
ありますね
Um, can I see that?
あの…
それ 見せてもらっていいですか？
（横溝）うん？
何だ？　桐山　お前も胃痛か？
What, Kiriyama? You have stomach pain too?
Stomach
Medicine
のむか？
やるよ　いっぱいあっから
Want some?
Keep it.
I've got plenty.
うん？　いやいや 桐山！
まず おめでとうだよ
Whoa, hey, Kiriyama!
Before that, congratulations!
You're the Rookie King!
取ったな 新人王
…て あれ？　桐山？
Uh...
Huh?
Kiriyama?
（零）急に 頭の中いっぱいに—
Suddenly the only thing I could think about was Hina,
curled up like a little ball on the floor the night before last.
おとといの夜の 彼女の
小さく丸まった背中が浮かんだ
For the Parents: Field Trip Schedule
Kiyomizu Temple
Heian Shrine
Lunch
Free Time (Shinkyogoku)
Ginkaku-ji Temple
Dinner
Kiyomizu Temple
Heian Shrine
Lunch
Free Time (Shinkyogoku)
Ginkaku-ji Temple
Dinner
Kyoto Station is just one stop away with the bullet train!
京都駅まで 新幹線だと ひと駅
Will I make it?
間に合うか？
ううん　行く
No, I'll go.
I have a feeling that I need to go.
行かなきゃダメな気がする
It feels like if I don't,
…でないと 私は—
I'll regret it down the line, even after becoming an adult,
この先 ずっと
大人になってからも—
years from now.
何年も ずっと
後悔するような気がする
（零）新京極(しんきょうごく)まで
To Shinkyogoku!
Damn it!
くそ！　いないか
She's not here?
Of course she's not.
（零）そうだよな
こんな行き当たりばったり…
Like I could find a junior high student who doesn't have a phone
よく知りもしない町で—
in a town I barely know by running around randomly,
携帯も持ってない中学生相手に—
“新京極で自由行動”って
ヒントだけで…
with "free time in Shinkyogoku" as my only hint.
何やってんだ 俺
What the hell am I doing?
What should I do?
（女子学生）どうしよう？
（零）あっ…
I can't make up my mind.
（女子学生Ａ）迷うなぁ
（女子学生Ｂ）ね〜っ？
I know, right?
Wow, that's so cute!
That's Hina's junior high school uniform.
（零）ひなちゃんの中学の制服…
Right?
Hey, where's Kiriyama?
（男子学生Ａ）あれ？　桐山は？
（男子学生Ｂ）知らねえ
I don't know.
It's fine, right?
（男子学生Ｂ）
いいんじゃねえ？　いなくても
This is our free time.
Checkmates Within 5-7 Moves
（男子学生Ｃ）自由行動なんだし
自由に行動してんじゃねえ？
So he's free to do what he wants.
Oh, that's right.
（零）ああ そうだ…　思い出した
I remember.
Not here.
ここじゃない
Someone who's all alone...
（零）こんな笑い声の中には—
won't be found amid all this laughter.
独りぼっちの人間はいられない
いられるわけがない
She couldn't be here.
Oh, that's right.
（零）ああ…　そうだ
彼女は いつも 泣きたくなると…
Whenever she feels like crying,
ひとりで川に…
she heads for the river...
by herself.
向かっていた
Rei?
零ちゃん？
Wh-What?!
どうして？　えっ？
How?! Huh?!
Why?!
えっ なんで？
なんで ここにいるの？
What are you doing here?!
How?!
（ひなた）どうして？
（零）あっ…　えっ…　え〜っと…
U-Um... Well, uh, let's see...
その…　え〜っと…
胃が痛いって言ってたから
どうしてるかなって思って…
You said your stomach hurt,
so I was wondering if you were okay.
…で あっ そうだ
So... Oh! That's right.
先輩に よく効く胃薬を
もらったから それで…
A colleague gave me some stomach medicine that's supposed to be really effective, so...
ひ… ひなちゃん？
H-Hina.
Hina, you've been hanging in there.
ひなちゃん　頑張った
よく頑張ったね
I'm proud of you.
（零）ひなちゃんは
大声で泣きだして—
Hina loudly burst into tears
and didn't stop.
止まらなくて
どんどん熱くなって…
She got warmer and warmer.
Her uniform and head became sweaty.
制服も頭も汗ばんで—
The breeze off the river on this slightly cloudy day was chilly,
薄曇りの川風は
肌寒くて—
僕は—
so I was worried she would catch a cold.
彼女が風邪をひきやしないかと
心配で…
I was so worried...
ただただ 心配で しかたなかった
that I couldn't let go.
Kingdom (Part 2)
I wonder why I'm smiling
The night wears on as I trace it with a finger
In the oversized nooks of this world
My heart continues to melt away
Like the petals of a flower repelling the rain yet refusing to wither
All the things important to me have spilled out
Before I knew it I was all alone and I'd walked a great distance
I'd forgotten what my own voice really sounded like
And it was the strangest feeling
After dawn broke on that long night
I remembered as if it were all a dream
I gave myself up to that nostalgic eternity
And it seems like I can go on walking again
Next Episode Preview
Episode 32
I thought maybe it was a dream.
（ひなた）
夢かと思ったの
I was in a strange city, all alone, feeling lonely, and about to cry,
知らない町で
独りぼっちで—
心細くて 泣きそうに
なっていたら—
髪がクシャクシャに
なるほど走って—
when you came running over,
out of breath,
your hair tousled by the wind,
息を切らした あなたが
立っていたから
and stood before me.
Illustration: Maya Mineo
（あかり）
修学旅行 懐かしいな
Field trips bring back memories!
And when I think of Kyoto, I think of tea, rice cake shops, and cinnamon cracknels!
京都といえば 八ツ橋(やつはし)
お抹茶 わらび餅！
ああ
妄想が止まらない！
Oh, I can't stop thinking about it!